

Babatunde Abioye



UAE Investor, Resident



bmabioye@gmail.com



+971528421748



www.linkedin.com/in/bmabioye



Dubai | Abu Dhabi | Ajman



www.bmabioye.me

IT Consultant | IT Trainer | Support Specialist | Project Manager | Web Developer | Freelancer | Entrepreneur

CAREER SUMMARY

 Passionate technology enthusiast, eager to gain experience in business development, artificial intelligence, web3 technology and cloud solutions. 7+ years experienced IT manager, entrepreneur and business management consultant, involved in operational cost reduction, facilitating increased productivity, and suggesting improvement on procedures

EDUCATION

MBA | EXPECTED 2023 | QUANTIC SCHOOL OF BUSINESS & TECHNOLOGY

- Major: Master in Business Administration
- · Related coursework: Customer Discovery, Marketing, Accounting, Entrepreneurship, Cultural Intelligence

BACHELOR | 2011 | FEDERAL UNIVERSITY OF TECHNOLOGY, MINNA

- Major: Bachelor of Technology in Computer Science
- Minor: Mathematics
- Related coursework: Information Management, Software Design, Computer Installation, Operation Research

PROFESSIONAL CERTIFICATIONS

- Microsoft: Microsoft Azure Administrator June 2021
- CompTIA: CompTIA A+ CE March 2021
- Google: Google IT Support Professional March 2021

SKILLS & ABILITIES

COMPUTER SKILLS

• FINANCIAL, ACCOUNTING SOFTWARE

- QuickBooks Setup, Installation and Configuration Advanced User
- Tally Setup, Installation and Configuration Intermediate User
- Sage Peachtree Advanced

BUSINESS MANAGEMENT SOFTWARE

- Bitrix24 Installation, Configuration, Development Advanced User
- Salesforce CRM Setup, Installation and Configuration Advanced User
- Microsoft Dynamic 365 Installation, Configuration Intermediate User

• GRAPHICS, DESIGN MULTIMEDIA

- Adobe Photoshop, Gimp Intermediate User
- CorelDraw, Inkscape, OmniGraffle Advanced User

OPERATION SUPPORT SOFTWARE

- Slack, Zendesk, Freshdesk SurveyMonkey, Jira Setup, Configuration Advanced User
- Microsoft Teams, Zoom, Teamviewer, Amazon Workspace, Setup, Configuration Advanced User

PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES

- JavaScript, PHP-Laravel, HTML, ReactJS, MSQL, CCS, JSON, YAML, NodeJS, Express, MongoDB Advanced
- Python-Django, Go, Java, Bash, C#, Scripting, VueJS Intermediate
- Go, Java, C#, C++, Ruby Beginner

CLOUD COMPUTING AND PROTOCOLS

- Microsoft Azure Certified Administrator
- AWS, GCP, DigitalOcean, Vultr, Configuration, Deployment Advanced
- Containerized Deployment Kubernetes, Docker, Podman, Jenkins, CI/CD Intermediate
- Virtualization VMWare, VirtualBox, GNS3, Hyper-V Configuration, Deployment Advanced

SYSTEM AND NETWORK ADMINISTRATION

- Linux Server Fedora, RedHat, Ubuntu Deployment, Configuration Advanced
- Windows Server Active Directory, DNS, DHCP, Group Policy Configuration, Deployment Advanced
- macOS Server DEP/MDM, CSR Deployment, Configuration, Management Intermediate
- Operating Systems Windows, macOS, Linux Installation, Deployment, Configuration Advanced
- Networking OSI Model, TCP/IP, Routing, Switching Installation, configuration Advanced
- Server Software & Protocol Apache, Nginx, IIS, SSH, SFTP Installation, Configuration Advanced

CUSTOMER SUPPORT

 Helped 100+ SMEs using technology to make their business simple, maximize profit, scale better and increase sales by 35% or higher year on year integrating inventory management and point of sale system to reduce paperwork and promote prompt and effective customer service delivery

COMMUNICATION

• Excellent oral, verbal and written communication skills in English. Beginner Chinese and Arabic speaker, reader.

LEADERSHIP

- Devised a Loan Management Application thus improving the cash in-flow by 25% within 3-months for a group of 1000+ people while serving as the lead technical advisor
- Built 3000 dollars' worth of business from scratch in 24-months of being self-employed, offering IT services and business management solutions in an economy with stringent means of business execution
- Managed a dynamic multi-functional team of 20+ people as chief technology officer and achieved 98% customer feedback using measurable, repeatable and scalable support system to resolve technical issues and suggest a new solution whenever necessary

TRAINING

• Trained 20+ college students in installation, configuration and troubleshooting of SOHO networks, broadened their information technology skills by 30% while over 50 teachers obtained relevant computer skills

EXPERIENCE

CEO | GEEXSE INTERNATIONAL FZE, UAE | NOV 2021 - TILL DATE

Initiated an IT firm to fill a gap in web3 technology solutions and offer exceptional training service.

IT SUPPORT - FREELANCER | SELL SYSTEMS, CHICAGO, USA | JUNE 2021 - NOV 2021

- Championed the clients' technical support, work closely with sales to foster high customer satisfaction and generated a 25% gross profit within 3 months
- Configured Bitrix24 CRM on RHEL Linux Server deployed on AWS to manage customers' leads, sales, and VoIP solution, achieved a 12% increase in customer patronage

IT CONSULTANT | COUNTRY KITCHEN VENTURES, NIGERIA | AUGUST 2017 - MARCH 2021

- Coordinated, collaborated and launched an eCommerce store to improve and expand business outreach by 30% or more within 24 months, increased sale turnover by 12% OoO
- Overhauled the obsolete IT infrastructure, researched security concerns, inefficiencies and restructured onpremises workloads which resulted in a 45% improvement in the department's operation output
- Orchestrated a profit increase of 2 million QoQ per outlet, implemented an inventory management system to handle purchases, supplier's payments and sales' transactions

FOUNDER - CLIENT SERVICES | LOVELAMP SYSTEMS, NIGERIA | MAY 2015 - MARCH 2021

- Championed the management of cross-functional departments, developed company-wide training and knowledgebase system to enhance staff productivity by 35%
- Innovated ticketing system for customer's service management, trimmed cost by 30% and lowered office overhead by 10%
- Assembled and imaged user workstations, created user accounts and profiles, installed updates and security
 patches for the smooth running of the front-desk offices in multiple outlets

OFFICE SUPERVISOR | AIRTEL SHOP, NIGERIA | AUGUST 2014 - MAY 2015

- Oversaw service desk operations, coordinated schedules and on-call coverage in an efficient manner attained a 95% customer satisfaction rating
- Monitored daily operations, work orders, resolved customer inquiries, ensured 24/7 network's confidentiality, integrity and availability

CUSTOMER CARE REP | MTN NIGERIA | FEB 2012 - AUGUST 2014

• Resolved customers' complaints on mobile devices, escalated unresolved issues to the L2 technical team and follow up accordingly to promote customers' satisfaction and confidence

ADDITIONAL INFO

DRIVING SKILL

Driving License – First Issued 2014 – [FRSC, Nigeria]

INTERESTS

• Loves reading, computing, research, travelling, healthy lifestyle with sport and fitness

DESIRED WORK TYPE

• Contract, Part-time, Partnership, Affiliate, Freelance, Full-time.